Guide to the Waldemar H. Fries Audubon research papers, 1805-1980.
Fries, Waldemar H., Audubon research papers
- Series I. American Folios: Correspondence and Notes
  - Princeton University, 1958-1972 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Talk at Princeton University, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    Includes transcripts of the speech and the Princeton University Weekly Bulletin, May 9, 1959
  - Princeton University, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    Includes photographs and copies of James Audubon's correspondence, 1830s
  - The Providence Athenaeum, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 49)
    Includes brochures, transcripts of Trustee Meetings (1830s), "Audubonia: Notes from the Diaries", by R. C. Murphy and a list of Folio plates/prints held by the library.
  - Bernard Quaritch Ltd., 1968-1972 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Regarding Constantine Rafinesque, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Notes on "Audubon Adventures", from "Dukedom Large Enough", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Regarding John Hampden Randolph, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Regarding Robert Ray, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    Includes a copy of Ray's will.
  - Duncan H. Read, 1964-1968 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Joseph Verner Reed, 1957-1971 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Regarding L. Reed (of New York), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Regarding William James Rees, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Richard J. Reynolds, 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - John and Mable Ringling Museum of Art, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Rosedown Plantations, 1957-1967 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Anna Wells Rutledge, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - St. Louis Mercantile Library, 1957-1968 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    Includes copies and transcripts of the library's annual report, 1858.
  - Salem Anthenaeum, 1957-1960 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - San Francisco Art Institute, 1957-1972 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Regarding Joseph Seabury, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Morris Schapiro, 1957-1964 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Regarding Gustavus Schmidt, 1958-1965 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Arthur R Sharp Jr., 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Regarding George C. Shattuck, 1958-1962 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    Includes sale catalogues, and a copy of the "Harvard Medical Alumni Bulletin", Summer 1961.
  - Shelburne Museum, Inc., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Regarding Gideon B. Smith, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 72)
    Includes reprint of the "Bulletin of the History of Medicine" article on Smith, Sep-Oct, 1961.
  - Smithsonian Institution, United States National Museum, 1968-1971 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Regarding Stanley Smith, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Sotheby's, 1959-1962 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - South Carolina Library, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - University of South Carolina, 1957-1971 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    Includes news clippings, a list of Folio plates/prints held by their library and transcripts and photographs of correspondence and reports of the South Carolina State Legislature.
  - University of Southern California, 1957-1966 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by their library, and a copy of "Coranto, Journal of the Friends of the Libraries", Spring 1966.
  - The University of the State of New York, 1957-1962 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Regarding William Stergis, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Regarding P. G. Stuyvesant, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - California State Library, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Regarding Robert J. Hubbard and H. J. Lutcher Stark, 1953-1969 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by Lutcher.
  - Nelda C. and H. J. Lutcher Stark Foundation Museum of Art, 1958-1974 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    Includes news clippings, a copy of "Coranto", Spring, 1966, and a list of Folio plates/prints held by the foundation.
  - Notes on and transcript of Audubon-Bakewell correspondence with Miss Gifford, 1789-1838, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - H. J. Lutcher Stark, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - H. J. Lutcher Stark, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 87)
    Includes a list of composite Folio plates held by him.
  - Regarding Samuel Swartout, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Mrs. Frederick R. Swigart, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Syracuse University, 1959-1971 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - University of Texas, 1957-1961 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Regarding Alexander Telfair, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Regarding Augustus Thorndike, 1957-1959 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - The Toronto Public Library, 1957-1968 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - University of Toronto, 1957-1970 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Regarding Frederic Tudor, 1960-1962 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Howard-Tilton Memorial Library, Tulane University, 1958-1967 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Regarding Carl Tucker, 1957-1974 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Morris Tyler, 1958-1973 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Carroll S. Tyson, 1962-1968 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Union College, University of New York, 1957-1973 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    Includes news clippings, newsletters (1971), photographs of John J. Audubon's correspondence (1840s), and a list of Folio plates/prints held by the library.
  - Regarding Vail, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Richard van Hoosear, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Regarding Jeremiah van Rensselaer, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Regarding William P. van Rensselaer, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Vassar College, 1957-1973 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    Includes catalogues, brochures, a copy of "Audubon and his Great Auk", The Ontario Naturalist, September 1969, and a list of Folio plates/prints held by their library.
  - University of Virginia, 1957-1971 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    Includes a copy of "Audubon Letters", 1826-1840, Boston-The Club of Odd Volumes, Vol II.
  - Regarding Joseph M. Wade, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Regarding Joseph E. Walker, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Regarding Frank Walters, 1958-1961 (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Regarding James Watson Webb, 1960-1969 (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Regarding Daniel Webster, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - Western Reserve University, 1958-1961 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Regarding John P. Wetherill, 1958-1966 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - C. V. Whitney, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Regarding George Wigglesworth, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Williams College, 1959-1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Regarding Langdon Wilks, 1958-1962 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Louise Jenkins Winston, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Winterthur Museum, 1958-1967 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Regarding Thomas Lindall Winthorp, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - The University of Wisconsin, 1957-1970 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Warren R. Howell, 1958-1960 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Yale University - Henry Farnam Set, 1961-1968 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Includes photographs of plates, a biography of Farnam in the Yale Obituary Record, a list of Ornithology books in their libraries, and a list of Folio plates/prints held by the library.
  - Yale University - Francis P. Garvan Set, 1957-1969 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Includes a list of Folio plates/prints held by their gallery.
  - Joseph R. Young, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Includes news clippings and a list of missing Folio plates/prints in his collection.
  - Regarding Thomas Young, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Series II. European Folios: Correspondence and Notes
  - Regarding the set of Her Most Excellent Majesty Queen Adelaide, England, 1961-1967 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - His Most Christian Majesty, Charles X, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - His Majesty Phillipe I, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Her Royal highness Mademoiselle d'Orleans, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Regarding the Prince of Massena, Paris, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - His Grace the Duke of Rutland, London, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Lord Fitzwilliam, 1966-1973 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Includes a list of Folio prints/plates at Wentworth House
  - Regarding the Countess of Ravensworth, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - The University of Edinburgh, 1958-1973 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    Includes a list of Folio prints/plates at their library.
  - Regarding Henry Witham, Esq. Lartington, 1967-1973 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - The Society of Writers to Her Majesty's Signet, Edinburgh, 1958-1968 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    Includes a list of Folio prints/plates originally held by them.
  - John Rutter, Esq. M.D. Liverpool, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Docton Bickersteth, Liverpool, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Regarding Armorer Donkin, Esq. Newcastle-upon-Tyne, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Yorkshire Philosophical Society, York, 1959-1967 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Regarding John William Clough, 1962-1967 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Joseph S. Crompton, Esq. Eshotton Hall, Yorkshire, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Regarding Thomas Walker, Esq. Killingbeck, 1962-1968 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Leeds Philosophical and Literary Society, 1959-1967 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - John Marshall, Esq. Headinglay, Leeds, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Regarding Major H.S. Greg, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Edward Lloyd, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - The Manchester Society for the Promotion of Natural History, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Chetham's Library, Manchester, 1957-1973 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    Includes a booklet on the library and a list of Folio prints/plates at the library.
  - G.W. Wood, Esq. Manchester, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Regarding Mrs Greenbank Rathbone, 1960-1967 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Regarding John Geroge Children, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Carnarvon, The Earl of London, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - S.P. Atkins, Esq. Walbrook, London, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Regarding the Right Honorbale Earl of Derby, Pro-Zoological Society, 1959-1967 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    Includes an account of his correspondence with Audubon, in Forest and Stream, June 1909.
  - The Right Honorable Earl of Spencer, London, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - J. Bradley Martin, 1955-1962 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Joseph John Gurney, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Darbyshire, Manchester, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - John Blackwall, Manchester, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - A. J. C. Baker, Esq. Prowin Park, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Reverend Edward Craig, Edinburgh, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - The Hunterian Library, The College of Glasgow, 1959-1969 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - John Buddle, Newcastle upon Tyne, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - The York Subscription Library, 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Kirk Patrick, London, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Regarding T. B. L. L. baker, Esq. Christ Church, Oxford, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - University Library, Cambridge, 1959-1968 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    Includes a list of Folio prints/plates at the library.
  - Regarding George Thackeray, Provost, King's College, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - The Cambridge Philosophical Society, 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - The Fitzwilliam Museum, Cambridge, 1959-1968 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    Includes a list of Folio prints/plates at the museum.
  - The Fitzwilliam Museum, Copies of Receipts, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Christ Church, Oxford, 1958-1974 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - The Radcliffe Science Library, Oxford, 1959-1968 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - James Pickering Ord, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - The Right Honourable Viscount Milton, London, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - The Library of the Royal Institute of France, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Ministry of the Interior, France (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Regarding M. Pitois, Agent, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 54)
    Includes copies and transcripts of his correspondencw with John J. Audubon, 1836.
  - Mrs. Warden (London), n.d. (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Hearne, bookseller, London, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Henry Ellison, Yorkshire, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Benjamin Smith (M.P), n.d. (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - The Right Honourable Earl of Bradford, London, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Thomas Fract, Esq. Gorton Hall, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - John Reeves, Esq. Birmingham, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Birmingham Old Library, 1958-1967 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Joseph C. Dyer, Esq. Manchester, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Thomas Walker Ravensfield, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - George L Fox, Yorkshire, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Haarlem Library, Holland, 1958-1968 (Box 8, Folder 66)
    Includes copies of John J. Audubon's correspondence and a list of Folio prints/plates at the library.
  - Regarding Euphemia Gifford, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 67)
    Includes a copy of her will, 1841.
  - Regarding Euphemia Gifford, 1963-1969 (Box 8, Folder 68)
    Includes negatives.
  - Fort Charles - Perran, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Regarding G. R. Lane Fox, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Regarding Sir John Tobin, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - His Grace the Duke of Buccleuch, 1969-1973 (Box 8, Folder 72)
    Includes negatives and newsprint.
  - Regarding His Royal and Imperial Highness The Grand Duke of Tuscany, 1959-1969 (Box 8, Folder 73)
    Includes information on the libraries of Florence in various volumes of the Book Collector.
  - London Institution, 1958-1972 (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - John Page-Phillips, Regarding Benjamin Phillips, Esq., 1965-1970 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - Transcripts of Benjamin Philip's correspondence with John J. Audubon, 1837-1849, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - Copies of Audubon-Phillips Correspondence, 1837-1849, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Henry J. Bohner, Esq, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 78)
    Includes a list of Folio prints/plates at Leningrad.
  - Charles J. Warde, Esq. Walcomb, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - The British Museum, 1958-1967 (Box 8, Folder 80)
    Includes photographs, and a list of Folio prints/plates at the museum.
  - British Museum of natural History, 1957-1968 (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - British Museum, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - His Grace the Duke of Northumberland, 1957-1969 (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - Regarding the Earle of Harwicke, 1959-1969 (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - Sir Jacob Astly, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - Public Library of Victoria, Melbourne, 1957-1968 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - National Museum of Victoria, Melbourne, 1957-1961 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Victoria B.C. Provincial Library, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Copenhagen, 1957-1967 (Box 8, Folder 89)
    Includes a list of Folio prints/plates at the Copenhagen Bibliotek.
  - Le Bibliothequ de l'Institut de France, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - Bibliotheque du Museum d'Histoire Naturelle, 1963-1967 (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Bibliotheque Nationale Department des Estampes, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - Baron Cuvier, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - French Letters, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - Colonel Thorne, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 95)
- Series III. Collateral Files: Sets in America
  - Regarding John Abbot, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    Includes information on Abbot in the Georgia Historical Quarterly, June 1959, and in the Auk, July 1896, and October 1942.
  - Regarding John James Abert, in Auk, April 1905, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Acknowledgements, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    Includes a manuscript of acknowledgements.
  - The Adams Papers, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Apologia, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    Includes a manuscript for "Apologia".
  - The London Athenaeum, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 59)
    Includes copies of newsprint, London 1838, an article in Auk, April 1916 on the number of sets of the Double Elephant Folio published, and negatives.
  - Regarding John Bachman, 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    Includes news clippings and an article in Auk, April 1929 on letters of Bachman to Audubon.
  - Copy of a paper on vultures by John Bachman, November 1895, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Regarding James Backhouse, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Regarding Spencer Fullerton Baird, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 63)
    Includes copies of "Spencer Fullerton Baird and the purchase of Alaska", Proc. of the American Philosophical Society, April 1954, and an account of letters of Audubon and Baird in Auk, April 1904.
  - Mrs. Donald Bakewell, 1961-1973 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Thomas Bakewell, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 65)
    Includes a biography in The Cardinal, 1935-1938.
  - William Bartram, in the Auk July 1913, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Regarding Walter Horton Bentley, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Nicholas Berthoud, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Thomas Bewick, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 70)
    Includes a set of cardboard-framed illustrations
  - Regarding Bien Chromolithographs, 1957-1971 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - List of Bien Chromolithograph Locations, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Bien Chromolithographs - List of Plates, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 73)
    Includes copies of sale catalogues and transcripts of texts on the Chromolithographs.
  - Bien Chromolithographs - Latter Press and Prices, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 74)
    Includes copies of sale catalogues.
  - Binker - For Birds of America, 1839, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Charles Lucien Bonaparte, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 76)
    Includes transcripts and copies of John J. Audubon's correspondence with Bonaparte, 1820s-1830s, and notes on Bonaparte in the Auk, April 1923
  - Thomas Mayo Brewer, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 77)
    Includes his Reminiscences of J. J. Audubon in Harpers Monthly Magazine, Vol LXL-365, and a biography
  - Captain Thomas Brown, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 78)
    Includes notes on his work, in Auk, April 1903 and October 1919, photographs and negatives.
  - Regarding Fanny Kemble (Mrs. Pierce Butler), 1958-1965 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    Includes a copy of "Mistakes in Fanny Kemble's Journal", Georgia Historical Quarterly, March 1960
  - John Calvert, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 80)
    Includes copies and photographs of John J. Audubon's correspondence.
  - Julia Jarvis, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Regarding Mark Catesby, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    Includes biographies, copies of illustrations and sale catalogues.
  - China Set at Natchez, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    Includes copies of the National Geographic Magazine, February 1949.
  - Chinese Art, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - The College of Physicians, Philedelphia, 1960-1964 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    Includes a copy of J. J. Audubon's correspondence with Richard Harlan, John Townsend and John Bachman in Fugitive Leaves from the Library, October 1963
  - William Cooper, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Includes copies of correspondence between Cooper and Charles Bonaparte, 1828-1829
  - Copper Plates I, 1962-1966 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Copper Plates II, 1958-1974 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Copper plates - List and Manuscript, 1960s, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Copper Plates, 1960s, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Includes copies of articles in Auk, 1907, 1908, 1934, American Literary Gazette, 1870, Forest and Stream, 1896, and in the John Hoy Special Collections, 1845
  - Copper Plates - List and Photographs, 19602, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - English Copyright Act, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Regarding Herman F. Cuntz, 1957-1968 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Jacques Louts David, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Regarding Ruthven Deane, 1957-1960 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Regarding M. Eugene Delessert, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - The Diary of Philip Hone, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Dorsey E. G. letters, 1844, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Royal Worcester Doughty Birds, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Includes sale catalogues and reviews.
  - Drawings, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Includes sale catalogues and reproductions of early Audubon drawings
  - David Eckley, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Economic Conditions, 1826-1840, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Includes a copy of parts of "A Hundred Years of Merchant Banking", by John Brown
  - George Edwards, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Includes papers on his north work on American birds
  - Eggs, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Engravings and Numbers, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Engraving, from the Universal Receipt Book, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Engraving, 1960-1969 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    Includes catalogues from the Audubon Exhibit, Cabildo, Feb-March 1960
  - Errors, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Regarding Edward Everett, 1968-1970 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Includes copies and transcripts of his correspondence with John J. Audubon
  - Exhibitions, 1961-1970 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Flowers and Plants, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 26)
    Includes a copy of "Audubon's Lily Rediscovered", Popular Science Monthly, April 1877
  - George William Featherstonehaugh, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 27)
    Includes copies of his papers, 1832
  - Birds as Food, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Ford Collection Letters, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Charles Stephen Francis, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Regarding Louis Agassiz Fuertes, 1960s, 1970-1972 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    Includes biographies, reviews, and reproductions of his paintings.
  - Mrs. Alice Walworth Graham, 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - John Gould, The Birds of Australia, 1967-1972 (Box 5, Folder 33A-B)
    Includes sale catalogues
  - George Bird Grinnell, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 34)
    Includes a copy of "Some Audubon Letters" by Grinnell. April 1916
  - Regarding Sir Edward Hallstrom, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Regarding E.F Hanaburgh, 1957-1969 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    Includes "A Checklist of the First Issues of the Plates in the First Folio Edition" by Hanaburgh, 1941
  - Dr. Richard Harlan, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 37)
    Includes copies of his correspondence, 1820s.
  - Edward Harris, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Robert Havell, 1959-1973 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    Includes photographs and news clippings
  - Robert Havell, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Legends (Chapter), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Havell Genealogy, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 42)
    Includes biographies and genealogical trees, in Print Collectors Quarterly, 1916.
  - Regarding John Henslow, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Philip Hone, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 44)
    Includes a copy of "The Diary of Philip Hones", 1927.
  - Henry Howland Raymond, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Glossary, Copy of Original, O.B., Vol IV, page 68, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - List of Paintings Harvard University, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - The Iconography of Manhattan Island, 1498-1909, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Birds of America Index, 1932, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Robert Jameson, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 50)
    Includes a copy of parts of "Audubon the Naturalist", by Francis Herrick, 1938.
  - Regarding William Jardine, 1963, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    Includes sales catalogues, and a copy of parts of "Audubon the Naturalist", by Francis Herrick, 1938.
  - Johnson Reprint, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Regarding John Keats, 1958, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Mrs. Fanny Kemble, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Kentucky Ornithological Society, 1968-1970 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    Includes copies of the Kentucky Warbler, May 1966, 1970.
  - Geoffrey Keynes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 56)
    Includes a copy of Country Life, 6 April, 1951.
  - Regarding Joseph Bartholomew Kidd I, 1961-1963 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    Includes a copy of Fries' paper "Joseph Bartholomew Kidd and the Oil Paintings of Audubon's Birds of America, in the Art Quarterly, 1963.
  - Jared Kirkland, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Regarding Joseph Bartholomew Kidd II, 1961-1964 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    Includes sales catalogues, and a copy of "Audubon Oil Painting", in the Audubon Magazine, n.d.
  - Alexander Lawson, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 60)
    Includes biographies and discussions of his work in Auk, Jan 1916 and July 1917, and copies of his correspondence with Bonaparte
  - Edward Lear, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Ledger 'B' Photographs, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Legends and Audubon's Signature, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 63A-B)
    Includes a photographs and negatives
  - Legends of the First Ten Plates, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Legends - Corrections, 1961-1970 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Legends, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 66)
    Includes photographs and carbons of legends.
  - Legends (Extra copies of first 10 plates with locations), 1973 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Edward Frederick Leitner, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    Includes copies of his biography in Bulletin of the History of Medicine, December 1972
  - Charles Alexander Lesueur, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Lithograph, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    Includes illustrations from the Art Quarterly, Vol XXIX No. 2, 1966
  - William Home Lizars, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 71)